<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<pbcoreDescriptionDocument xmlns="http://www.pbcore.org/PBCore/PBCoreNamespace.html" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.pbcore.org/PBCore/PBCoreNamespace.html https://raw.githubusercontent.com/WGBH/PBCore_2.1/master/pbcore-2.1.xsd">
  <pbcoreAssetType source="PBCore">Program</pbcoreAssetType>
  <pbcoreAssetDate annotation="Azatlyk Radiosy (Turkmen Service) web distribution date" dateType="distributed" source="PBCore">2019-06-06</pbcoreAssetDate>
  <pbcoreIdentifier source="RFERL CMS ID">29916023</pbcoreIdentifier>
  <pbcoreTitle titleType="Program" titleTypeAnnotation="English title">Wasteland</pbcoreTitle>
  <pbcoreTitle annotation="Turkmen title" titleType="Program">Gazagystanda öldüriji sowet mirasy</pbcoreTitle>
  <pbcoreSubject ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q5347379" source="Wikidata">Effects of nuclear explosions on human health</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreSubject ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q53732481" source="Wikidata">Nuclear test site
</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreSubject ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q13065634" source="Wikidata">environmental pollution</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreSubject ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q210112" source="Wikidata">nuclear weapons test</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreSubject ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q757666" source="Wikidata">Semipalatinsk Test Site</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreSubject annotation="Director of Qaragandy Ecomuseum" source="Local">Dmitry Kalmykov</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreSubject annotation="Kazakh school teacher" source="Local">Bolatbek Baltabek</pbcoreSubject>
  <pbcoreDescription annotation="English summary" descriptionType="Summary" descriptionTypeSource="PBCore">Forty years of Soviet nuclear bomb tests have left a toxic wasteland in Kazakhstan. The nuclear explosions have stopped, but Russia still rents vast swathes of Kazakh territory for missile tests that critics say are devastating for the environment and its inhabitants. For this documentary, we traveled on September 18-30 across Kazakhstan to tell the stories of the people who live amid this lethal legacy. It was filmed in Semipalatinsk, Taysoygan, Kapustin Yar test sites, in Qaragandy, Atirau, Uralsk, Astana (Nur-Sultan) cities and in remote villages. </pbcoreDescription>
  <pbcoreDescription annotation="English translation " descriptionType="Transcript" descriptionTypeSource="PBCore">Sometimes I say with bitter irony that Kazakhstan is a truly free country: you can do what you want. You can go to a nuclear test site. You can go to a rocket test site. 

I’d rather we were dying in an actual war while carrying weapons. It’s like we’re being shot and killed, but we don’t know who’s responsible. Is it radiation, politics, or something else?

This test site is used by another country to develop new weapons to kill more people. 

The test explosions in the atmosphere were conducted to measure their impact on the human body. That makes us guinea pigs.

Islam says that man comes into the world to be tested. 

The Test

Let’s go.

We’re traveling beyond the reach of civilization. For hundreds of kilometers around us, there are no power lines, no filling stations, no mobile phone coverage. 

This huge area of steppe is still known as the Semipalatinsk test site. 
It was here that the Soviet Union gave violent birth to the nuclear age.
For forty years, a massive experiment was conducted on the land, water, animals, and people. 

Dmitry Kalmykov, Director of the Karaganda EcoMuseum:
After a nuclear explosion, the test plane caught fire from the blast. It was so hot that the engine melted and turned into a puddle. 

Dmitry Kalmykov, director of the Karaganda Ecomuseum, has been collecting artifacts from the test site for more than 20 years. He believes the main problem is not radiation, but lack of adequate information. 

Dmitry Kalmykov: We’ve asked police officers, doctors, teachers, and public officials about it. You’d be amazed by their answers.  When we asked if they lived in the test area, their answers are random. Some say yes, others say no.  There’s no relation to reality. No one informs people, and they can’t tell a polluted area from a clean one. 

This lake was formed in the crater left by a nuclear explosion in 1965. 
It was part of a plan to provide easier access to water for the residents of the arid Kazakh steppe.
There has been little discussion about radiation.
According to Soviet propaganda, the water in the nuclear lake posed no threat to the people who relied on it.  
Research has shown that this water is completely harmless to people.
Many people used to fish here and sell or eat their catch. Kazakhstan later designated the lake as a site affected by nuclear testing. But it’s still accessible to the public and seems to have an abundance of carp. 
Do you know there’s radiation here? 
We know.
Aren’t you afraid to eat fish from here?
Are they biting?
Yes. 
The residents of the nearby villages continue to fish here. They can see the lake and touch the fish, but they don’t feel the radiation. 

Dmitry Kalmykov: There are thousands of people living near the borders of the test site. If you look at the map, the border seems to bend around the villages, technically leaving them outside of the test area. But these villages are a stone’s throw from the test site.

Schoolteacher Bolatbek Baltabek lives in Sarzhal, one of the villages just outside the test site. He remembers being asked to leave his house before nuclear tests. 
Bolatbek Baltabek: My parents and I would go outside. At some point, the earth would start shaking. One of my scariest childhood memories is that someone would hang himself almost every month. They say it was the impact of the testing. During my second year at the school, one of the students, Kuanysh, died of brain cancer. Then another girl, Marzhan, died of leukemia. My classmate Zukhra died of leukemia a year after she finished school. Her sister Zhanar died five years later. 

Bolatbek Baltabek: Most people here die of mysterious causes. They just get sick and die. It’s like an undeclared war. I’d rather we were dying in an actual war while carrying weapons. It’s like we’re being shot and killed, but we don’t know who’s responsible. Is it radiation, politics, or something else? 

Studies show that the radiation left in the wake of nuclear tests can cause cancer and other illnesses, including mental disorders. But locals have no way of knowing what the impact might be on their own lives. 

Bolatbek Baltabek: The test site is no simple case. You hear about it and watch the mushroom clouds, while we live under them like flies around a boiling cauldron. Politicians seem to think of us as flies. But we are humans. 
Our whole lives are a test site. Islam says that man comes into the world to be tested. We are tested twice: by God and by man. 

Mukhtar Tayzhan, activist: The test explosions in the atmosphere were conducted to measure their impact on the human body. That makes us guinea pigs. We used to be a [Soviet] colony and we’re still a colony. 
 
This is ground zero of the first Soviet nuclear test, conducted in 1949. Dozens of nuclear and thermonuclear explosions formed many more craters in the decades that followed. Today, 30 years after the last explosion, the level of radiation here is 100 times higher than normal. But the former test site remains open to visitors. Anyone can come here. 

Dmitry Kalmykov: Sometimes I say with bitter irony that Kazakhstan is a truly free country: you can do what you want. You may go to a nuclear test site, you may go to a rocket test site. There’s nothing to stop you. 

The town of Kurchatov was the scientific center serving the Semipalatinsk test site. After the collapse of the Soviet Union, its population dropped by nearly half. The National Nuclear Center is still the biggest employer in the town. But most of the test site and military infrastructure has crumbled.  
Nearby are the remains of what was once a secretive military town. 
Chagan didn’t appear on Soviet maps, although over 10,000 people lived here. Today, the name is on the map, but the town an empty shell.  
After the collapse of the Soviet Union, the nuclear tests in Kazakhstan came to an end. Russia removed the nuclear weapons. Underground missile silos were blown up, and Kazakhstan became a nuclear-free country. The Semipalatinsk test site was officially closed. 
But Moscow struck an agreement with the Kazakh government to lease three test sites, along with the space launch facility at the Baikonur Cosmodrome. The three sites are used for ongoing tests of conventional weapons, including strategic and ballistic missiles. In total, the rented territory covers 86,000 square kilometers – an area larger than Austria. 
Russia pays Kazakhstan $20 million a year, or $2.30 per hectare. 

Dmitry Kalmykov: Once every few years there’s a technical failure, and a rocket explodes and falls from space. The debris can fall from space into your back yard or a cow pasture. This is an upper stage -- the booster of a Proton rocket. As you can see, it’s the biggest gift from space. 

Location graphic: Taysoygan

Galymzhan, is there a metal part of the probe?
No.
Eh?
No. 
Where is it?
It’s gone.
Where’s the metal?
It’s gone.
What about the tray?
Thrown away, too.
My son says it was all sold as scrap metal.

80-year-old Tabyldy Akhmetov has been a shepherd his whole life. He has lived in Taysoygan for more than 30 years. Aside from his family, there are no other residents for many kilometers in any direction. 
Akhmetov went to check if all the scrap metal had been sold, as his son said. 

Where do you think this debris comes from?
From the [test] zone, of course. 

The kids have been collecting these things in the area to sell as scrap metal. Ten years ago, there were a lot of buyers. 

What about now?
They’re all long gone.
There used to be a lot of metal. There’s still some scattered on the steppe.  

Russia launches test missiles from its military site at Kapustin Yar – and when there’s a malfunction, Taysoygan is the landing site. 
The village used to be part of a testing zone until Moscow changed its lease in 2016, handing part of the territory back to Kazakhstan. 
Now Taysoygan village is outside the test zone – but it remains in the path of falling objects. 
Residents are used to finding fallen chunks of metal, though they say this has not happened since 2016.

Tuzgenbay Urbisinov, the head of the local council of elders, has repurposed a metal sphere as a water tank for his outdoor shower.  

Tuzgenbay Urbisinov: Balls like this fall from the sky when there are launches. They have pipe and hose connectors on both sides.
How do you use it?
To transport manure or snow in winter.
There’s a lot of stuff like this in the test area.
People from China and other countries used to come and buy it all. 
 Wow, that’s cool. Look, a star! 

Locals filmed this unidentified object over Kapustin Yar on July 4, 2018, while trying to guess what it could be. 

A meteorite! 
A meteorite, look!
I hope it doesn’t explode nearby.
It’s so bright in the village! Wow!
I hope it doesn’t fall on our heads. 

Early the next day, Lupkan Akhmedyarov, chief editor of the Uralskaya Nedelya newspaper, arrived to record the remnants of the crash.

Lupkan Akhmedyarov: The Russian military said it was a meteorological probe used for weather forecasts. But in my opinion, we’re dealing with missiles here. The Russian military never confirms it, and neither do the Kazakh authorities. They just say: “It’s for the Russian side to comment on.”

Akhmedyarov believes Kazakh officials avoid raising the issue with Russia in order to maintain smooth relations with their powerful strategic partner and military ally. 

Lupkan Akhmedyarov: We need to acknowledge officially that the Kazakh test site leased to Russia has a negative impact [on the environment]. But this is a political decision that the local authorities are in no position to take. I’m more than convinced that even officials in Astana are in no position to decide on that. 
This test site is used by another country to develop new weapons to kill more and more people. 

Kulpash Bozova, a widow and retiree, spends her days caring for her disabled daughter, Gulmira, in the village of Khan Orda. 
Another of her daughter’s died, after suffering a similar condition, at the age of 15. 
She says doctors have blamed her children’s health problems on the family’s proximity to the test site. 

Kulpash Bozova: She’s been like that since birth. I’ve been looking after her all her life. She doesn’t understand much. During the day, we go outside and play a little. At night, I tie her to the bed so that she doesn’t throw things around or break them. 

Dmitry Kalmykov: The locals don’t have satellite phones, internet access, or access to weather forecasts. They don’t have any of that. That’s why they‘re angry: the missiles are flying, [the Russians] pay for it, and sometimes there are crashes with toxic fuel leaking out. But what do [local people] get? What’s in it for them?

Demonstration
I say this to our authorities and the Russian authorities: if you are a friendly country, it’s time to close these sites, because they are killing us. 

Activist Mukhtar Tayzhan has been trying to warn the public about what he says are the severe health risks posed by the rocket tests. 

People have gotten used to living this way. It’s been 70 years. No one tells them what kind of missiles are tested there, what kind of fuel is used. It’s heptyl.

In 2013, a Russian Proton rocket crashed shortly after its launch from the Baikonur facility in Kazakhstan. 

According to official data, 600 tons of the rocket fuel known as heptyl spilled onto the ground and into the air.

It was the first time many Kazakhs had heard the name of the toxic substance. 

Doctors and environmental researchers say heptyl poses serious risks to human health.

Gulnara Taumanova, emergency physician and environmental activist, Atyrau: How can we perform tests on our children? It’s like an open-air lab here.
We’ve been an independent state for years. What have we done for the people? 
They still live like they always have. How can this be tolerated? 

Physician and environmental activist Gulnara Taumanova has been studying the negative effects of rocket launches in the area for many years. 

Gulnara Taumanova: We’ve found very dangerous radioactive isotopes in our medical tests. We’ve found radioactive tritium [a form of hydrogen] in blood samples. The tests get worse every year. The children’s samples are much worse than their grandfathers’ or great-grandfathers’.

Mayragul Sadirova lives in the village of Zhiyekkum near the test site. 
Her 5-year-old son Alikhan has Down syndrome. 
There’s no connection between these two things. But both provide her with government financial support.

Mayragul Sadirova: The disability benefit is 64,000 tenge [$170 a month]. Plus $12 in compensation for [living near] the test site. 
There’s always the roar of rockets from the test site. You look up at the sky and see the explosions. 

This is what the official document looks like, which confirms $12 monthly compensation for living near the test site.

They are paid peanuts. Does it mean they live in a contaminated area? What are they paid for? If it’s a contaminated area, they should be relocated. 
People continue living on the test site, or near it, and using contaminated land. You can’t check every cow. The meat of these cows and horses ends up at the market. We eat it. It’s not a smart thing to do, to put it mildly. 

We tried to schedule interviews with several officials in the capital, Astana, but they declined to comment.

Activists, on the other hand, are ready to raise their voices.

Artist Askhat Akhmedyarov has used performance, videos, installations, and political protests to make himself heard. 

Askhat Akhmedyarov: If I can explain the threat in this way, then my mission is complete. 

Pasha Kas	
My name is Pasha Kas. I’m a street artist from Kazakhstan.
Another artist, Pasha Kas, staged his protest at the test site itself with this reproduction of Edvard Munch’s “The Scream.”

[voice from Pasha Kas video]
[something else before this?] This is silence. 
Dmitry Kalmykov: This issue can be solved easily. It’s a simple issue of management. The research is done. The polluted spots have been identified. The government has to build a fence. If there are people living nearby, the government must buy houses for them on clean land. It’s not many. Maybe 20,000 or 30,000 families. They should buy nice houses on clean land, that’s all! They should just say that we’ve put our polluted Soviet past behind us. Now live and be well. Forget the past. But this issue has been ignored for decades. 

[Credits:]
The Test
A film by Harutyun Mansuryan
Correspondent  Sanata Urnaliyev
Graphics by Juan Carlos Martinez
Editing Harutyun Mansuryan</pbcoreDescription>
  <pbcoreDescription descriptionType="Comments" descriptionTypeAnnotation="Keywords" descriptionTypeSource="PBCore">horse, steppe, Sarjal/Sarzhal, teacher, interview, broll, barbed wire, antelope, Kurchatov, Mirjisimk, museum, Qaragandy, village, livestock, agriculture, labor, Chagan, ghost town, artificial lake, graffiti, Munch Scream, drone footage, dombra (musical instrument), camel, Atyrau Region, Taysoyghan/Тайсойған/Тайсойган, Orda, Bisen, Zhiekkum, Kapustin Yar, Uralsk region, Nur Sultan, city center, government building, Soyuz rocket, Proton rocket, launch system, launch vehicle, </pbcoreDescription>
  <pbcoreGenre ref="https://www.ebu.ch/metadata/cs/ebu_ContentGenreCS.xml" source="EBU ContentGenreCS">Documentary</pbcoreGenre>
  <pbcoreRelation>
    <pbcoreRelationType source="PBCore">Is Related To</pbcoreRelationType>
    <pbcoreRelationIdentifier annotation="RFERL Pangea MAM IDEC: Project identifier for compiled raw materials, b-roll, and interviews.">PR-19000725</pbcoreRelationIdentifier>
  </pbcoreRelation>
  <pbcoreCoverage>
    <coverage ref="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Q232" source="Wikidata">Kazakhstan</coverage>
    <coverageType>Spatial</coverageType>
  </pbcoreCoverage>
  <pbcoreCreator>
    <creator affiliation="RFE/RL" annotation="Kazakh Service">Radio Azattyq</creator>
    <creatorRole annotation="Producing service" source="PBCore">Producer</creatorRole>
  </pbcoreCreator>
  <pbcoreCreator>
    <creator affiliation="Multimedia">Harutyun Mansuryan</creator>
    <creatorRole source="PBCore">Producer</creatorRole>
    <creatorRole source="PBCore">Editor</creatorRole>
  </pbcoreCreator>
  <pbcoreCreator>
    <creator affiliation="Kazakh Service">Sanat Urnaliyev</creator>
    <creatorRole source="PBCore">Producer</creatorRole>
  </pbcoreCreator>
  <pbcoreContributor>
    <contributor affiliation="Broadcast Operations">Roman Kupka</contributor>
    <contributorRole source="PBCore">Camera Operator</contributorRole>
  </pbcoreContributor>
  <pbcoreContributor>
    <contributor affiliation="Multimedia">Juan Carlos Martinez</contributor>
    <contributorRole source="PBCore">Graphic Editor</contributorRole>
  </pbcoreContributor>
  <pbcorePublisher>
    <publisher>Current Time English</publisher>
    <publisherRole source="PBCore">Publisher</publisherRole>
  </pbcorePublisher>
  <pbcorePublisher>
    <publisher affiliation="RFERL, Inc." annotation="Turkmen Service">Azatlyk Radiosy</publisher>
    <publisherRole source="PBCore">Publisher</publisherRole>
  </pbcorePublisher>
  <pbcoreRightsSummary>
    <rightsSummary annotation="Restrictions">Restrictions:
1. Videos 00:42-00:46, 00:59-01:10, 02:12-02:20, 03:28-04:01, 08:07-08:15, 10:29-11:15, 19:47 to 20:16: copyright Reuters. Must on-screen credit.
2. Video 15:57-16:31, 20:16-20:55, 23:25-24:23 YouTube videos, Fair Use.
3. Still photo image used 16:53-17:06 and video 17:37-17:52: copyright Uralskaya Nedelya newspaper.
</rightsSummary>
  </pbcoreRightsSummary>
  <pbcoreRightsSummary>
    <rightsSummary source="RightsStatements.org">In copyright</rightsSummary>
  </pbcoreRightsSummary>
  <pbcoreInstantiation annotation="English clean version ready for language localization: no titles, subtitles or narration track">
    <instantiationIdentifier annotation="IDEC" source="RFERL PANGEA MAM">PR-19000750</instantiationIdentifier>
    <instantiationIdentifier annotation="Title original" source="RFERL PANGEA MAM">FINAL_English_Clean_MAM.mxf</instantiationIdentifier>
    <instantiationDate dateType="created">2019-05-03</instantiationDate>
    <instantiationDate dateType="ingested">2019-07-11</instantiationDate>
    <instantiationDigital>application/mxf</instantiationDigital>
    <instantiationStandard annotation="1.2" profile="OP-1a">MXF (XDCAM HD 35)</instantiationStandard>
    <instantiationLocation>RFERL PANGEA MAM</instantiationLocation>
    <instantiationMediaType source="PBCore">Moving Image</instantiationMediaType>
    <instantiationGenerations source="PBCore">Master production</instantiationGenerations>
    <instantiationFileSize unitsOfMeasure="byte">5444273608</instantiationFileSize>
    <instantiationDuration>00:25:54:21</instantiationDuration>
    <instantiationDataRate annotation="VBR" unitsOfMeasure="bit/second">28012007</instantiationDataRate>
    <instantiationTracks>3</instantiationTracks>
    <instantiationChannelConfiguration>Track 768: 1 channel, Track 1024: 1 channel, Track 768: 1 channel, Track 1024: 1 channel</instantiationChannelConfiguration>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Original language" source="ISO 693-3">rus</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Original language" source="ISO 693-3">kaz</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="Other_Codec_List">MXF TC / MXF TC / SMPTE TC</instantiationAnnotation>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="Format_Commercial_IfAny">XDCAM HD 35</instantiationAnnotation>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="Format_Settings">Closed / Complete</instantiationAnnotation>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="FrameCount">38871</instantiationAnnotation>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="PackageName">Source Package</instantiationAnnotation>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="Encoded_Application_CompanyName">Adobe Systems Incorporated</instantiationAnnotation>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="Encoded_Application_Name">Premiere Pro</instantiationAnnotation>
  </pbcoreInstantiation>
  <pbcoreInstantiation annotation="English version with bug, titles. subtitles, and narration.">
    <instantiationIdentifier source="File name">FINAL_English_Best_Quality.mp4</instantiationIdentifier>
    <instantiationDate dateType="created">2019-05-03</instantiationDate>
    <instantiationDate annotation="Current Time English web distribution date" dateType="distributed">2019-05-08</instantiationDate>
    <instantiationDigital>video/mp4</instantiationDigital>
    <instantiationStandard profile="Base Media / Version 2">MPEG-4</instantiationStandard>
    <instantiationLocation source="RFERL Video Server filepath">V:\Video\Wasteland\Finals\FINAL_English_Best_Quality.mp4</instantiationLocation>
    <instantiationMediaType>Moving Image</instantiationMediaType>
    <instantiationGenerations source="PBCore">Master distribution</instantiationGenerations>
    <instantiationFileSize unitsOfMeasure="byte">10859899955</instantiationFileSize>
    <instantiationDuration>00:25:54:21</instantiationDuration>
    <instantiationDataRate annotation="VBR" unitsOfMeasure="bit/second">55876617</instantiationDataRate>
    <instantiationTracks>2</instantiationTracks>
    <instantiationChannelConfiguration>Track 2: 2 channels (L R)</instantiationChannelConfiguration>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Original language" source="ISO 693-3">kaz</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Subtitles and narration track in English" source="ISO 693-3">eng</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Original language" source="ISO 693-3">rus</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="FrameCount">38871</instantiationAnnotation>
  </pbcoreInstantiation>
  <pbcoreInstantiation annotation="Turkmen web version">
    <instantiationIdentifier source="File name">64d391be-6d06-4363-a07d-5363b0c482aa_fullhd.mp4</instantiationIdentifier>
    <instantiationDate dateType="broadcast">2019-06-06</instantiationDate>
    <instantiationDate dateType="captured">2019-11-25</instantiationDate>
    <instantiationDigital>video/mp4</instantiationDigital>
    <instantiationStandard profile="Base Media">MPEG-4</instantiationStandard>
    <instantiationLocation>https://www.azathabar.com/a/29984315.html</instantiationLocation>
    <instantiationMediaType source="PBCore">Moving Image</instantiationMediaType>
    <instantiationGenerations source="PBCore">Copy: access</instantiationGenerations>
    <instantiationFileSize unitsOfMeasure="byte">569098784</instantiationFileSize>
    <instantiationDuration>00:25:55:16</instantiationDuration>
    <instantiationDataRate unitsOfMeasure="bit/second">2926616</instantiationDataRate>
    <instantiationTracks>2</instantiationTracks>
    <instantiationChannelConfiguration>Track 2: 2 channels (L R)</instantiationChannelConfiguration>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Original language" source="ISO 693-3">kaz</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Original language" source="ISO 693-3">rus</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Narration track" source="ISO 693-3">eng</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationLanguage annotation="Subtitles" source="ISO 693-3">tuk</instantiationLanguage>
    <instantiationAnnotation annotationType="FrameCount">38891</instantiationAnnotation>
  </pbcoreInstantiation>
  <pbcoreAnnotation annotation="Cataloger name" annotationType="Cataloging note">VAUGHNJ</pbcoreAnnotation>
</pbcoreDescriptionDocument>
